DMYTRO BONDAR

dagassacoop@gmail.com · 437-818-2477 · github.com/DagassaCoop · linkedin.com/in/dmytro-bondar

I'm a Frontend Developer with more than 5 years of experience in designing, developing, shipping, and maintaining large-scale web applications with user-friendly, accessible and responsive UI/UX. I have proven myself as a responsible software engineer, paying special attention to the architecture of my projects and the sequence of execution of assigned tasks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

99Ravens Toronto, Canada

Frontend Developer, UI

September 2024 - Now

- Implementing foundation elements for project UI design system.
- Designed new components based on UI foundation with optimized performance.
- Delivered features optimized for maximum speed and scalability.
- Worked closely with backend developers, designers, and product managers to deliver cohesive solutions.

Innopharma Technology

Dublin, Ireland

FullStack Developer, SmartX

November 2022 - May 2024

- Converted an entire web app from AngularJS to Vue, optimized and reorganized the codebase, and integrated TypeScript for enhanced functionality and maintainability. My actions resulted in a 27% increase in the site's performance and reduced the time required to debug and add new features by 3 times.
- Came up with and developed a new product feature, which significantly expanded the functionality of the software. Oversaw all stages of development, from creating early concepts and gathering customer feedback to implementing highly scalable UI/UX on the client side and APIs on the server side.
- Designed permission system based on OAuth 2 protocol to remote control users features accessibility.
- Led 2 training sessions on TypeScript: one for developers covering tools and use cases, and another for the management staff highlighting the advantages and necessity of the technology.
- Developed a new automation cycle for our product based on thorough research into chemical reactions and consultations with our in-house chemist.
- Created Docker setup for client side, modified CI/CD pipeline and deployed it on Jenkins.

Design Studio Goracio

Kharkiv, Ukraine

Frontend Developer

August 2020 - October 2021

- Created over 10 desktop and mobile web projects using React and React Hooks, ensuring responsive and user-friendly designs with high level of web accessibility
- Optimized customer website based on CSM by using build in tools and codebase reorganization and increased it's performance by 31%.
- Worked on new features for customers websites based on CMS, enhancing functionality and user experience.

EDUCATION

Kharkiv Polytechnic Institute

Kharkiv, Ukraine

Bachelor of Computer Science

September 2018 - May 2022

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS, Docker

Technologies: React, Next, Vue, Node.js, Git, Bootstrap, MUI, GraphQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Apollo, Jenkins, Vitest,

React Testing Library, Selenium, Sass/Less, Pug

Tools: Webpack, Vite, Figma, ESLint, Jira, Storybook

VOLUNTEERING

The Better Future For All

Frontend Developer

Toronto, Canada September 2024 - Now

- Creating new UI & UX components and features.
- Reviewing current and new codebase.
- Collaborate with Cross-Functional Teams.

PROJECTS

Movies Search TypeScript, React, Vitest, RTL, OAuth

- Developed a highly scalable web application using a combination of TypeScript and modern stack of React technologies such as Redux Toolkit, React Router 18, React Query and MUI.
- Designed complex infrastructure and API connectors for integration data from TMDB database.
- Covered the entire application by Unit tests by combination of Vitest and React Testing Library.
- Implemented user authorization by OAuth 2 protocol.